Anita Reschke Collection of Opera Recordings
Anita Reschke Collection of Opera Recordings
1988-1990
Reschke, Anita.
1.5 linear ft.
Personal (i.e. non-commercial) recordings of various opera performances on standard audiocassettes; many are from the Metropolitan Opera but there are also performances from the Bayreuth Festival, Chicago Lyric Opera, London, and the Syracuse Symphony. Also includes a few personal recordings of speakers at Jesuit gatherings.
3194829
Biographical History
Nothing is known of the donor of this material.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Anita Reschke Collection of Opera Recordings consists of personal (i.e. non-commercial) recordings of various opera performances on standard audiocassettes. Many of the recordings are from the Metropolitan Opera but there are also performances from the Bayreuth Festival, the Chicago Lyric Opera, the Syracuse Symphony and unspecified performances in London. Many, but not all, of the tapes are annotated with the names of the major performers.
There are also a few recordings of speakers on religious subjects at Jesuit gatherings.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by composer.
Subject and Genre Headings
Bayreuther Festspiele.; Lyric Opera of Chicago.; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); Operas -- Sound recordings.; Operas -- United States.; Audiocassettes.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to tapes requires advance notice for creation of use copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Anita Reschke.
Inventory
- Audiorecordings
  - Auber, Manon Lescaut, undated; 2 tapes (Box 1)
  - Bellini, I Puritani, undated; 2 tapes (Box 1)
  - Bellini, Norma, undated; 2 tapes (Box 1)
  - Berg, Wozzek, 1/6/1990; Metropolitan Opera; 2 tapes (Box 1)
  - Berlioz, Requiem, 1987; Syracuse Symphony (Box 1)
  - Boito, Mefistofele, 11/11/1989; 2 tapes (Box 1)
  - Borodin, Prince Igor, 9/16/1989; 2 tapes (Box 1)
  - Donizetti, Anna Bolena, 8/19/1989; 3 tapes (Box 1)
  - Form for ministry retreat, 1984; 7 tapes (Box 1)
  - Form for ministry retreat, Fall 1984; Fr. Pete Conroy, S.J.; 6 tapes; 3 are missing (Box 1)
  - Gershwin, Porgy and Bess, 1/27/90; Metropolitan Opera; 3 tapes (Box 1)
  - Giordano, Andrea Chenier, 9/30/1989; London; 2 tapes (Box 1)
  - Glass, Satyagraha, May 88; Chicago Opera; 2 tapes (Box 1)
  - Gospel of John, Fr. Richard Rohr (Box 1)
  - Gounod, Faust, 3/3/1990; Metropolitan Opera; 2 tapes (Box 1)
  - Haydn, Armida, 8/12/1989; 2 tapes (Box 1)
  - Homily, Bishop Harrison b/w Leoncavallo, Pagliacci, 10/7/89 (Box 1)
  - Humperdinck, Hansel and Gretel, 1988-1989; Metropolitan Opera; 2 tapes (Box 1)
  - Mascagni, Cavalleria Rusticana (Box 1)
  - Meditation and dying, Lawrence Freeman, undated; 4 tapes, 2 copies each of 2 tapes (Box 1)
  - Meditation, 3 tapes (Box 2)
  - Montamezzi, L'Amore dei tre re, 9/30/1989; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Moussorgsky, Kovanschina, 3/26/1988; Metropolitan Opera; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Mozart, Apollo et Hyacinthus, 8/12/1989 (Box 2)
  - Mozart, La Clemenzo di Tito, 6/16/1990; Lyric Opera; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Mozart, Cosi Fan Tutte, 1/20/1990; Metropolitan Opera; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Mozart, Don Giovanni, 6/3/1989; Lyric Opera of Chicago; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Mozart, Don Giovanni, 4/14/1990; Metropolitan Opera; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Mozart, Die Entfahrung aus dem Serail, 3/24/1990; Metropolitan Opera; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Mozart, Le Nozze de Figaro, 12/31/1988; Metropolitan Opera; 3 tapes (Box 2)
  - Offenbach, La Perichole, 9/23/1989; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Ponchielli, La Gioconda, 2/3/1990; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Puccini, La Boheme, 3/31/1990 (Box 2)
  - Puccini, Edgar, 8/5/1989; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Puccini, Manon Lescaut, 3/17/1990; Metropolitan Opera; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Puccini, Turandot, 1/12/1990; Metropolitan Opera; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Rachmaninoff, Aleko, 9/16/1989 (Box 2)
  - Saint-Saens, Samson et Dalila, 2/17/1990; Metropolitan Opera; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Schoenberg, Gurrelieder, 5/31/1989; Chicago Symphony; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Strauss, Die Fledermaus, 6/9/1990; Lyric Opera; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Thomas, Mignon, 11/25/1989; 3 tapes (Box 2)
  - Verdi, Aida, 1/7/1989 - Metropolitan Opera; 2 tapes (Box 2)
  - Verdi, Aida, 11/18/1989; 2 tapes (Box 3)
  - Verdi, Ernani, 8/5/1989; 2 tapes (Box 3)
  - Verdi, La Traviata, 2/10/1990; Metropolitan Opera; 2 tapes (Box 3)
  - Verdi, Il Trovatore, 10/7/1989; 2 tapes, tape #1 is missing (Box 3)
  - Verdi, Il Trovatore, undated; 2 tapes (Box 3)
  - Wagner, Parsifal, 1989; Bayreuth Festival; 4 tapes (Box 3)
  - Wagner, Tannhauser, 5/20/1989; Lyric Opera of Chicago; 3 tapes (Box 3)
  - Wagner, Die Walküre, 4/7/1990; Metropolitan Opera; 3 tapes (Box 3)